ABDELLAH BECHERAIR

in @abdellahbecherair

□ abdellah.becherair04@gmail.com

🕥 @Becherair-Abdellah 🔍 +213666364546

PROFILE SUMMARY

Software engineer Frontend developer specialized in React js | Next js | javascript | Tailwind | Redux with 3 years of experience, I build interactive and scalable user interfaces, I can work on very large and complex projects by choosing the necessary techniques and tools with communication and collaboration with teams to reach the common goal, My passion is to build powerful software and web applications through my continuous learning.

EDUCATION

Kasdi Merbah University

Sep 2021 - Present

B.S. Computer Science

courses: data structures, Algorithms, OOP, Databases, Os, Information systems, Networking, Graphs

WORK HISTORY

Frontend Developer & UI UX | Ayrime Company - UK (remote)

Nov 2023 - Mar 2024

- Develop a Warehouse Management System (WMS), the system was open-source and allowed for new modifications to be added.
- The backend was developed using the Django framework and Python, and it runs on a Docker environment and is open source.
- Building and designing the company's UI/UX.
- Developing a WMS interface using React.js and Redux.

Frontend Developer & UI UX | CNTIC Club - ALG

Oct 2023 - Mar 2024

- · Building and designing the club's UI/UX.
- Developing a site-specific dashboard for managing the club and its members using React.js.
- Offering courses and workshops in web development and frontend development within the university.

SKILLS

- Technical Skills: Vcs (Git), Github , HTML5 & CSS3, Javascript ,React js | Next js | Redux , API integration, Tailwind, Modules Bundlers (vite, WebPack).
- Soft Skills: Effective communication, Decision making, Public speaking, Constructive criticism, Consultation.
- Languages: Arabic (Native), English (good).

PROJECTS

The following projects are some of the core projects I had worked with, not all

Wearhouses Managment System (WMS) | next & react , Javascript ,docker , Tailwind

Present

- Cloning an open-source backend developed using Django and Python.
- · Running the backend on a Docker environment.
- Working on improving the user interface using Next js.
- APIs integration, Authentication, Authorization.
- UI UX design

- Creating functions for the ability to display and create my own articles on my blog .
- Creating and displaying event projects .
- Using React JS and Redux for state management .
- UI UX design

TOPICS OF INTEREST

- System Design .
- API Design .
- distributed system .